# George Messiha

☐ +2 (012) 0088 5832 • ☐ georgemessiha22@gmail.com • in georgesamir22 ☐ 27236809 ☐ georgesamir22 ☐ georgemessiha22 ☐ george.samir301

Resume Viewer June 30, 2020

Dear Sir or Madam,

With a Bachelor's degree in Information Engineering Technology and hands-on experience using Python languages to create and implement software applications, Confident I will be an asset to your projects.

Enjoy being challenged and engaging with projects that require me to work outside my comfort and knowledge set, as continuing to learn new languages and development techniques are important to me.

Your listed requirements closely match my background and skills. A few I would like to highlight that would enable me to contribute to your bottom line are:

- o Highly skilled in designing, testing, and developing software
- o Thorough understanding of data structures and algorithms
- o Knowledgeable of back-end development best practices
- Hands-on software troubleshooting experience

Proven track record of proper documentation for future maintenance and upgrades I've attached a copy of my resume that details my projects and experience in software development. I can be reached anytime via my cell phone or via email.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to speaking with you about this opportunity.

Sincerely yours,

#### George Messiha

Attached: curriculum vitæ

# George Messiha

☐ +2 (012) 0088 5832 • ☑ georgemessiha22@gmail.com • **in** georgesamir22 ☑ 7236809 ②georgesamir22 ☑ georgemessiha22 ③george.samir301

DevOps for life, Software Engineer by day, Entrepreneur by night. Building to make people's life easier. Volunteer by heart. feeding my eager to learn, implement, create to reach my ultimate potential. Looking forward to be the Next Game Changer.

## **Education**

The German University in Cairo

Cairo, EG 2011-2016

Bachelor of Networks and Information Engineering Technology

Bachelor Thesis Topic: Security of Cloud Computing
Saint Fatima International School - Nasr City

Thanwya Amma, Math Science

Cairo, EG 1997-2011

# **Experience**

### **Orange Business Services**

Cairo, EG

#### Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2018-Present

Jul 2017-Jul 2018

Building Orange's first automated reporting tool for every service performance and customizing the reports to Customer needs and requirements upon each SLA.

Detailed achievements:

- Help the team to collect relative data for clients on their business, clean data to find the performance and efficiency of the system and the network timing.
- Data modeling, system architecture, data loading from Big data warehouse HortonWorks to kafka and more streaming data tools, to visualize the data in meaningful charts in data analytic reports.
- o Tools: Hadoop, Spark, Python, HortonWorks, Django, Jira, Taiga, Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, Docker, Dcoker-Compose, Linux, Power BI, Web Scrawlers, Scrum, Agile DevOps framework

PayMob Cairo, EG

**Software Engineer**Building Vodafone Cash Backend.

Detailed achievements:

O Develop, test, debug and maintain cloud based solutions with python, nginx, AWS, Docker technologies.

- o Develop unit tests and work with Quality Control members Roles on solving the defects.
- Prepares and installs solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards, and programming. Embracing, utilizing the new wave of software development concepts (SaaS, Cloud Computing)

Nexus Edge Sao Paulo, Brazil

#### Remote Software Engineer

Dec 2017

Developing one of the most cognitive Marketing AI, helping to improve the teams communication, managing the development remotely. Maintaining development cycle.

### **BlueCloud Technologies**

Cairo, EG

#### Software Engineer

Feb 2017-Jun 2017

Building Docs Sharing Software addons in Microsoft Word. Detailed achievements:

- o Develop, test, debug and maintain web/windows cloud based solutions with MS .net technologies.
- o Develop unit tests and work with Quality Control members/Roles on solving the defects.
- o Prepares and installs solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards, and programming.
- o Embracing and utilizing the new wave of software development concepts (Software-as-a-service, Cloud Computing, ...etc.).

Aprcot Cairo, EG

#### Software Engineer

Jun 2016–Jun 2017

Building a tool to automate the Ads campaign for Social media(e.g. Facebook, Google, Instagram, Youtube) instead of registering for each campaign it automates the campaign follow the graph produce a peak notification, choosing the best plane with the best budget to reach the target. all of that is automated using our magnificent tool which use machine learning, AI, Restful and a lot of other applications to reach the campaign target.

Detailed achievements:

- o Develop, test, debug and maintain.
- o Tools: Bower, Gitlab, Jira, CSS, AngularJS, HTML, Gulp, Django, Rest Framework.

Internships..

#### The German University in Cairo

Cairo, EG

#### Junior Teaching Assistant

Sep 2015-Jan 2016

Helping the Teacher Assistant in the University in teaching Android Application developing. Helping students to do their tasks on time, solving any issues facing them or teach them any required skills.

Orange Egypt Cairo, EG

# Network Engineer Trainee

Did system provisioning work. Main Duties:

- o Security Analyzer.
- o Connect remotely to Offices' devices for troubleshooting.
- o Revise Offices' Firewalls policy.

Cairo, EG Xerox Sales & Representative Engineer Trainee Aug 2014

Did system administrative work. Main Duties:

- o Establish Network connection to Xerox remote Devices.
- o Maintain IT requirements for the devices to adapt for the network condition.
- o Build Xerox printer's Applications specially customized for the clients.

### Skills

Advanced

Language: Python, Java, Bash, LaTeX, Markdown Web-Frameworks: Django, Restframework, Flask

SysAdmin: Linux (Debian, Red Hat), Gitlab CI/CD, Docker, Ansible, Docker-Compose, Continues Delivery, Fabrics

Data Science: Pandas, NumPy, dataframes

Services: Gunicorn, WSGI, Apache2, HAProxy, Load Balancer

Team Tools: Agile, Scrum, Jira, git, Office, Scrapy, Swagger, Sphinx docs, readthedocs

Intermediate & Beginner.....

Language: PHP, GoLang, Rust, Elixir Web-Frameworks: Phoniex, Angular

Operating Systems and automation: Kubernetes Data Science: Bower, Hadoop, Spark, PowerBI

Services: Nginx

# Languages

Arabic: Native English: fluent Professional working proficiency Deutsch: Basic Basic words and phrases only

Cleaning Data in Python

Introduction to Data Visualization with Python

Interactive Data Visualization with Bokeh

**DataCamp** 

**DataCamp** 

Certificates & Awards	
PeopleCert PeopleCert DevOps Fundamentals: Effectiveness & efficiency beyond comparison	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2019
Udacity, ITI Deep Learning NanoDegree	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2018
Udacity, 1 Million Arab Coder  Data Analyst	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2018
DataCamp	
Courses	
DataCamp Introduction to Databases in Python	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp pandas Foundations	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017-2018
DataCamp Importing Data in Python (Part 1)	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017-2018
DataCamp Importing Data in Python (Part 2)	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017-2018
DataCamp	Cairo, EG

**DataCamp** Cairo, EG Intro to Python for Data Science Course 2017-2018

2017-2018

Cairo, EG

2017-2018

Cairo, EG

2017-2018

**DataCamp** Cairo, EG Statistical Thinking in Python (Part 1) 2017-2018

DataCamp Statistical Thinking in Python (Part 2)	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 1)	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 2)	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Intro to SQL for Data Science	Cairo, EG 2017-2018
DataCamp Intermediate Python for Data Science Course	Cairo, EG 2017–2018
DataCamp Manipulating DataFrames with pandas	Cairo, EG 2017–2018
DataCamp	Cairo, EG
Merging DataFrames with pandas  DataCamp	2017–2018  Cairo, EG
Network Analysis in Python (Part 1)  DataCamp	<i>2017–2018</i> <b>Cairo, EG</b>
Machine Learning with the Experts_ School Budgets  DataCamp	2017–2018 Cairo, EG
Supervised Learning with scikit-learn Course  DataCamp	2017–2018 Cairo, EG
Unsupervised Learning in Python Course	2017–2018
DataCamp  Deep Learning in Python	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
Tracks	
DataCamp Python Programming	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Python Programmer	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Importing Cleaning Data with Python	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Data Manipulation with Python	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Data Analyst with Python	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Machine Learning with Python Track	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
DataCamp Data Science	<b>Cairo, EG</b> 2017–2018
Udacity, ITI	Cairo, EG
Android Fundamentals	2016
Activities	
Masabeeh  Charitable NGO, Organizing weekly meetings for kids in Masr Gedida  Prepare workshops of games and help them with school. on other hand teach them to spell and wirth	<b>Cairo, EG</b> <i>May 2016–2017</i> e.
Math Teacher	Cairo, EG
Voluntary Education, Providing Education for kids from rural areas Teaching fifth primary students Math. Teaching second primary students English.	Sept-Dec 2015
APE (Association for Protection of Environment)	Cairo, EG
Culture Awareness Charitable NGO, Organizing camps for kids from rural areas Prepare workshops that teach them some crafts. Give presentations about: culture awareness, self est	2013–2015
development.	C-:
<b>EASE</b> Educational Charitable NGO, Organizing camps for High School Students	Cairo, EG  Jan 2012–May 2012

Educational Charitable NGO, Organizing camps for High School Students Jan 2012–May 2012

Role: Presenter. To Educate the High School Students more about life experiences and prepare them to face the future.